<PAGE>
	<VAR match="VAR_ORIGIN" replace="../" />
	<VAR match="VAR_CVSID" replace="$Id: jffs2.xml,v 1.1 2005/03/12 13:48:22 gleixner Exp $"/>
	<INCLUDE file="../inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_DOC" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_JFFS2" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="../menu1.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="../inc/content.tmpl" />

    <h2>JFFS2</h2>
    <p>
	JFFS2 provides a filesystem directly on the 
	flash, rather than emulating a block device. For more information,
	see <a href="http://sources.redhat.com/jffs2/">sources.redhat.com</a>.
    </p>
    
    <hr size="2" />
    	
    <h2>JFFS2 erase block size</h2>

    <p>Unlike the original JFFS, JFFS2 treats each erase block of the
    flash separately. It will never write nodes which cross from one
    erase block to another, and will not cope if it encounters a file
    system with such nodes. Any node which crosses an erase block
    boundary will be ignored by JFFS2, and the data it contains will
    be lost, causing the file system to be corrupted.</p>

    <p>If there's not enough space at the end of the current erase
    block to write a whole node, JFFS2 will leave it blank and
    continue writing to a new erase block.</p>

    <p>Also, JFFS2 always starts writing at the beginning of an erase
    block, and does not expect to find free space in the middle. Any
    free space in an erase block should go all the way to the end of
    the erase block. JFFS2 will print a complaint such as:</p>
    <div>
<pre>
jffs2_scan_empty(): Empty block at 0x0012fffc ends at 0x00130000 (with 0xe0021985)! Marking dirty
</pre>
    </div>	
    <p>if it finds free space in between the nodes in an erase
    block. This situation is harmless though - it's just a little bit
    of wasted space, that's all.</p>

    <p>Both of these situations can occur if you create a JFFS2 image
      with <tt>mkfs.jffs2</tt> using the wrong value for the erase
      block size (the <tt>-e</tt> option). The default is 64KiB,
      because that's the smallest erase block size you're likely to
      encounter often, and creating an image with smaller eraseblock
      size than the actual hardware is harmless -- it just gives
      annoying messages. If you see the messages mentioned above,
      check the erase block size of your device (look in
      <tt>/proc/mtd</tt> if you don't know), and create your JFFS2
      image for it with the correct <tt>-e</tt> option.</p>

		
	<INCLUDE file="../inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
